Guide to the George Durand Wilder papers, ca. 1897-1976
Wilder, George Durand papers, ca. 1897-1976
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George Durand Wilder papers, ca. 1897-1976
3241
George Durand Wilder, 1869-1946.
.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, published volume, notebooks, pamphlets, field notes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes notebooks, pamphlets, field notes, and other material on ornithology, mostly in China; Birds of Northeastern China by Wilder and Hugh Hubbard; correspondence of Wilder and his sons Theodore Wilder and Durand Wilder (George Durand Wilder, Jr.) and of Gertrude Stanley Wilder; volume of "Random Jottings" by Gertrude Wilder, including recollections of China missions and missionaries.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes notebooks, pamphlets, field notes, and other material on ornithology, mostly in China; Birds of Northeastern China by Wilder and Hugh Hubbard; correspondence of Wilder and his sons Theodore Wilder and Durand Wilder (George Durand Wilder, Jr.) and of Gertrude Stanley Wilder; volume of "Random Jottings" by Gertrude Wilder, including recollections of China missions and missionaries.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Wilder, George D. (George Durand), b. 1869.; Wilder, George D. (George Durand), b. 1869. Birds of northeastern China.; Hubbard, Hugh W.; Wilder, Durand.; Wilder, Gertrude Stanley. Random jottings.; Wilder, Theodore.
Subjects:
Missionaries--China.; Missions--China.; Ornithology.
Places:
China.
Form and Genre Terms:
Field notes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Notebooks and pamphlets, 1917-1969, regarding birds in China by Axel M. Hemmingsen; also other subjects by Dr. Ernest Hartert (in German); also "Migration Notes" by Wilder (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "1925 Migration Notes at Pei Tai Ho"; includes some correspondence to Wilder's son, Theodore Wilder (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ornithological materials including hand-drawn map with key to trees, Weihsien C.A.C. Compound, summer, 1944; newsclippings, magazine articles ( National Geographic), pages of Report of the Forest, Fish and Game Commission with plates by Fuertes, and a pamphlet by Wilder, 1904-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Nagamichi Kuroda (Tokyo)-Wilder correspondence, 1929-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "Index to 'Migration Notes'--Unpublished," 1943, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Ocean birds observed, Shanghai to NY, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous materials including "In Memoriam" (GDW); correspondence of Theodore and Durand Wilder (GDW Jr.), 1968-1975; also Hubbard to Durand, and copies of letters and messages from George and Gertrude Wilder, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Handwritten field notes in China during the years 1897-1943 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
- Small notebooks of field notes in China during the years 1897-1943 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
- Birds of Northeastern China (by Wilder and Hubbard) (Box 2)
- Vol. I: Keys and indices (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Vol. II: Passeres to Cuculi (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Vol. III: Striges to Galli (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Vol. I and II: Duplicate pages with some illustrations tinted (Box 2, Folder 7)
- "Random Jottings" by Gertrude Stanley Wilder, 1959 (Box 3)
- Letters of GDW written on his trip from China after being in the Weihsien Prison Camp in 1943 (Box 3, Folder 1)